Michael Hartmann

B.B.A. Specialization Finance Trinity Western University 778.872.6444 michaelphartmann.github.io MichaelPeterHartmann94@gmail.com

I am a recent business grad with experience in equity research and investment principles. I thrive on tackling obstacles and presenting solutions in intuitive ways. I have a deep knowledge of Microsoft Office and regularily use Excel to model equities. I have an interest in programming that has started in Python but continues to grow in extent and in breadth as I look to learn new languages and develop new tools. Beyond finance and programming I enjoy developing policy, specialty coffee, and helping others understand financial markets.

Education

Trinity Western University B.B.A. Specialization in Finance Graduated December 2019

Kwantlen University Entreprenuerial Leadership Attended Sep. 13 to Apr. 15

Skills

- Advanced user of Microsoft Excel, Word, and Powerpoint
- DCF Valuations and equity modelling through Excel
- Experience using API/structured data to extract information
- Intermediate proficiency in Python with limited experience in other programming languages
- Creating rational project plans and dynamically alter them according to project requirements
- Developing policy and guidelines for internal and external use
- Incredibly inquisitive and detail oriented in research and preparing reports
- Strong communication skills in both verbal and written mediums
- Synthesizing external and internal perspectives into meaningful and actionable plans
- Pursuing CFA Level I Summer 2020

Work Experience

TWU Student Managed Investment Fund

Portfolio Manager

September 2017 to April 2019

- Constructed the DCF valuation templates for fund use
- Pitched companies across different sectors
- Wrote fund investment guidelines and policy documents
- Developed hiring and meeting procedures
- Took part in validating pitches and ensuring accuracy of data

Starbucks

Shift Supervisor

January 2018 to May 2019

- Wrote morning orders according to inventory levels
- Maintained fast workflow while managing meal breaks
- Prioritized cleaning, maintenance and operational duties on an ongoing basis

Premium Woodcraft Homes & Beaver Brothers Framing

Framer, Carpenter, Concrete Work Summer 2016, Summer 2017, May 2019 to Present

- Work in a fast-paced team environment
- Work according to schedule needs overtime and weekends as needed
- Liase with other trades to make fixes and alterations
- Ensure quality and safety at every step

Qualifications

Bloomberg Market Concepts — March 2018

Eight hour self-directed course focused on equities, bonds, economic indicators and basic functionality of the Bloomberg Terminal.

Academic Reference Chen Liu (604) 513.2121 ext. 3310 Chen.Liu@twu.ca